Welcome to Business Central 2026
uh launch edition. This session is about
the new APIs we added for permissions,
approvals, and documents.
So why did we do this? What what what
does this help you with? Well, for for
documents, we are opening up for
automation on all the document types. in
the beginning only for getting the PDFs
then later in later versions of business
central we might open up for more and
then for um for internal controls for IT
departments you can now uh easily report
uh on that using copilot studio agents
or powerbi on all data related to
permissions and approvals. So let's just
quickly see what's going on here for
sales you have in 28.x like all of these
document types get APIs within the
purchasing area also 28.x X you get all
these areas with PDF so you can get them
in APIs inventory get even more all
these um ones um and finally for
assembly uh these two get APIs if you
want to learn more about document
reporting as a whole including these
APIs there's a breakout session for that
uh there's a link in the description so
you can learn much more about what we
did for document reporting not only the
new APIs
All right. So within permissions, we
have these five new APIs coming all the
way from permission sets down to who
actually has which users have different
permission sets. So we have a new API
that show all permission sets. You can
link to users and security groups that
use these. We have expanded permission
sets so you can also get from where
these permission sets uh are coming
which apps are introducing them. We have
security groups that also allows you to
navigate to the linked permission sets
and group members. So you can see from
this also who has kind of inside these
per security groups. permissions. User
permissions uh allow you to see all sets
assigned directly or inherited uh to
users and then uh access control uh all
all records related to that.
For approvals, we have also uh these new
seven APIs on workflows all the way down
to approval and posted approval entries.
So um
ability to see all workflows go uh
navigate from that to workflow steps
from work workflow step is a is its own
API you can navigate from there to
response options and then here you are
able to see all workflow step arguments
approver types approver ID and so on
for approvers you have an API for that
uh for each workflow approver type and
approval limit. So that allows you to uh
see who can do approve what to which
extent in uh in money. Um there's an
approvals user setup so you can see
approval change direct approver and so
on for a given user or all users. Uh you
can you can you can see all approval
entries as well as all posted approval
entries through these two new APIs.
Now everything related to this is
covered in more details in the IT
auditing session. So there's a breakout
session for there where we will also
introduce all the other things we added
within the IT audit area.
If you want to learn more, the the place
to go for as always for APIs is the AK
link aka.msbc
integration. And here you can learn
about everything in this topic including
all the new APIs which will be
documented uh here on API v2.
And that's it for for APIs. Um, I hope
you enjoy the other sessions here in our
launch edition. Look for our related
sessions in the co in down in the
description and u have a great uh
conference or a great um launch edition.
Thank you. Bye.
We have compiled a number of general
resources that we believe are key both
for partners but also uh business
central customers. Most some of these
are partner some of them are also for
customers. So the first one is called
aka.msbcall.
This is a partner resource for that
contains lists of every other aka link
that is needed for you to understand
anything about both the business central
product but also processes around it. We
call these aka links because they're
called aka.ms and then forward/
something. And with business central
links we all always prefix with BC and
then something. The next one is uh our
partner network uh social media for for
business central partners. Viva Viva
engage. So ak.msbc
viva engage is where you go and interact
with other partners. It's not open for
customers. So this is where you can ask
questions, interact with the product
group, interact with with with each
other. um in a in a closed network.
Second link, a third link is for both
partners and customers. We are called
office hours. So office hours is
something we do once or twice a month
from the product group engaging with the
community about new features or things
we want to discuss. Aka.msbc
office hours is the is the place where
you go to find out about upcoming
events. These are recorded. I believe
the recordings are available only to
partners, but the live events are
available to customers as well. Fourth
link is YouTube, our YouTube channel.
I'll talk about that uh in the next
slide and LinkedIn in the next slide. Uh
and then finally uh for for Microsoft
partners, the BC ak.ms/BC
partner portal is where you get um a lot
of the resources as a partner such as
compete decks, uh pitch decks and a lot
of other resources
for LinkedIn. This is our product
group's uh LinkedIn profile. We have 30K
or more followers. So both partners and
customers, this is the place where we
from the product group put in news and
small bits of information outside the
quote unquote official channel. So
follow us on on LinkedIn to learn what's
happening right now um in in this in the
around the product. Um and then uh also
on our YouTube channel, this is where
you're probably watching this aka.ms/bc
YouTube. We put in not only these launch
editions twice a year, but also co-pilot
and AI videos, shorts, tips and tricks,
technical deep dives under the hood. Uh
we even have this watch cooking where we
put little nuggets of of videos out for
new features that are even coming in on
the YouTube channel before uh they're
coming in the release notes. So watch uh
and maybe bookmark us on YouTube and
also notice all the playlists. So the
the content is also organized in areas
not only all the videos. So if you have
an area that has special interests such
as analytics um you can find an a
playlist and kind of see all the content
related to that. And that's it. That is
truly it. We won't uh there would be no
more. So, thank you for watching all the
way to the end and again have a great
day. Thank you.